Elayaraja S Front-end developer

# Elayaraja Subramanian

Front-end Developer

Phone: +91-9600321809 E-mail: raja5ramani@gmail.com

**Github:** <a href="https://github.com/ElayarajaSubramanian">https://github.com/ElayarajaSubramanian</a>

Portfolio: <a href="https://elayarajasubramanian.netlify.app/">https://elayarajasubramanian.netlify.app/</a>

Web and Graphic Designer having 12+ years of experience to secure a challenging position to utilize my skills and abilities in the field that offers professional growth while being resourceful, innovative and flexible.

#### Skills

Web technologies	Tools
HTML5	Adobe Experience Manager 6.1 & 6.4
CSS3	Adobe photoshop
JavaScript	Adobe illustrator
React	Adobe InDesign
SASS	Adobe premiere pro
Bootstrap	Adobe XD
jQuery	Sanity IO
Typescript	Bit.dev
NextJS	

# **Experience**

#### Oct 2014 - Present Team lead

Infosys BPM, Chennai

- Creating reusable components on Bit.dev for Sanity IO CMS
- Migrating legacy components from AEM to Sanity IO CMS
- Increased sales ~ 10% by creating newly designed pages using
  HTML5, CSS3, Javascript
- Implemented new content in AEM 6.1 and AEM 6.4 and played a major role in successfully deploying offer content
- Collaborated with UX team, Content team to sharpen newly designed pages and their content
- Collaborated with dev team to come up with easily manageable Content Fragment Model (CFM)

Elayaraja S Front-end developer

Collaborated with dev team to finalize the JSON for new AEM
 6.4 pages

 Conducted daily huddle meetings to discuss challenges and to share some best practices to make the process easy

## Nov 2013 - Sep 2014 Web designer

Habiliss systems pvt ltd, Chennai

- Created elegant web layouts and icons to helped to get more clients in UK
- Converted PSD to HTML and reduced work load for back end developers team in UK
- Collaborated with back-end dev team to fix UI issues

## Mar 2011 - July 2013 Graphic designer

Teledata marine solutions, Chennai

- Created elegant login and landing pages for marine students
- Created detailed PDF study materials using adobe indesign for marine e-learning courses
- Created videos using adobe flash which explains marine concepts in detail for marine e-learning courses

## Jan 2010 - Feb 2011 Graphic designer

Abink software solutions, Chennai

- Created attractive web layouts, brochures, logos for multiple
  level clients like hospitals, educational institutions
- Collaborated with dev team to learn more about programming, database

#### Education

#### 2005 - 2009 Bachelor of Engineering

JJ College of engineering and technologies, Trichy.

# **Courses and certifications**

- Completed Fullstack developer (MERN) course with GUVI
- Microsoft HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript Certification

Elayaraja S Front-end developer

• Type Writing (Higher & Lower) Certification

# **Key Competencies & Skills**

- Excellent development, analytical and logical skills
- Capacity to work in meeting deadlines
- Ability to go to the core of the problem and resolve
- Willing to learn and adapt to new challenges
- Have strong interpersonal skills, which provides with the ability to interact with end-users,
  managers and technical personnel
- Self-motivated, quick learner

# **Rewards & Recognition**

- Received spot award for my exemplary performance on handling the project
- Received extra miler award for supporting other teams in crucial projects
- Received site of the week award for the websites which I designed

## **Personal details**

Date of birth 28<sup>th</sup> May, 1987

Nationality Indian

Father's Name P. Subramanian

Permanent address 63, New street, Thuraiyur taluk, Trichy district, Tamilnadu - 621010

Temporary address No.7, Yamunai street, Ram nagar, Madipakkam Chennai - 600091.

#### **Declaration**

I hereby, declare that the information published above is correct according to my knowledge and conscience. I can be held responsible for any discrepancies in the above mentioned facts.

(Elayaraja S)